hello and welcome to the HamCrop Guide to GTNH Particle Physics
in this video
we will go over the upcoming Large Hadron Collider multiblock which will be added to GTNH in 2.9
this multiblock was designed and implemented by me
well mostly me
with a lot of help from many members of the dev team and GTNH community
that's right
the LHC is Literally HamCorp
you can try the LHC and all the other new 2.9 features now if you play on the dailies
please do that and find bugs for me so I can fix them
thanks
at the time of recording 2.9 is still in development
and the LHC and beamcrafting still require balancing and bug fixing
check the pinned comment to see if changes in how the system works have been made since this video
minor balancing changes are not going to be covered in that comment
the LHC is a replacement for the old compact Cyclotron or comet which will be removed
the LHC and beam crafting multites use the existing beamline mechanics
and are actually compatible with the beamline multites
in fact you may even be able to use the LHC to do beamline recipes
but that's not something that's been extensively tested at the time of recording this video
I can confirm that it's possible
but not if it's actually viable in the actual game
the beam line is technically still optional
but considering the LHC is not
I expect to see a lot more beamlines
the LHC will be the new method of obtaining Quark Releasing Catalysts
yes, long time HamCrop fans may be making the link now
this multi was indeed born entirely out of me being overly pedantic about particle physics
anyway, the LHC now gates Grade 8 water
the beamcrafter which can be used before you get an LHC
now gates Unknown Particles and the Quantum Anomaly
all recipes that formerly used particles as items now use particles as beams
particles no longer exist as items with the exception of the unknown particle
first, let's cover the basics of particles in GTNH
particles in beams travel as packets
similar to the research station computation packets
particle packets have four attributes
type, energy, amount and focus
type is the type of particle
so electron, muon, photon and so on
energy is the energy of the particle in electron volts
amount which is sometimes sort of inconsistently called rate here and there can be interpreted as the number of individual particles in the packet
this is what determines crafting speed in the beamcrafter
and is the quantity you want to maximize
focus is not relevant for the LHC and beamcrafting
but it's a quantity that represents the collimation of the beam
this matters for beamline
but we will completely ignore it in this video
next, let's talk about how the LHC actually works
I will continue based on the assumption that you have read the tooltip for details
the LHC takes any charged particle as input
and generates output depending on:
1. the energy of the collision and 2. which module you draw outputs from
the LHC has two modes accelerator and collider
it cycles once per second
and automatically switches from accelerator to collider when the player set acceleration cycle count is reached
in the interface
if you click this button
you are able to set two values
the target beam energy and the acceleration cycle count
once you set these and turn on the LHC
it will start accelerating the incoming beam
this input beam cannot have any of its four parameters change during operation
or the LHC will shut down
using the incoming beam's values as the starting point
the LHC will accelerate the beam in accelerator mode
meaning the beam energy increases once per cycle
if the beam energy reaches the player set target energy
further LHC cycles will instead increase the current beam amount
but how do you know what target energy to set
well, the beam energy serves one purpose
adding particle types to the pool of potential outputs
if you have an accelerated beam energy of E
then the collision energy when particles collide is 2 times E
the types of particles that can appear in the outputs now are simply all those particles whose mass is 2E or lower
so if you're targeting a particle of mass 100 giga electron volts
then set your target energy to at least 50 giga electron volts
then the collision is 100
and you can get these particles
there's no benefit to increasing energy beyond what you need
also, not all particles can appear in all modules
each LHC module can only produce a subset of particles
you can see this in NEI
the power draw of the LHC can be very high
since it increases quadratically with time
and it also scales with beam amount
that said, I have done an analysis of how the resulting crafting speed in the beam crafter scales with the power draw
and I found that it's best to do as many cycles as possible
the more cycles you do the closer
you get to perfect overclocking
details of this analysis are in an optional advanced section later in the video
OK, that was a lot
let's talk about how to use these particles
the Beamcrafter is a multi that takes fluid, item and particle inputs
the craft begins as soon as input items and fluids are detected
the machine then waits for particle inputs
which provide progress to the craft
no particles means no progress
the recipe does not shut down if the particle beams are interrupted
NEI shows the cumulative beam amounts required for the crafts
and energy is consumed constantly while the craft is going
note that at the time of recording the beamcrafter does not work with the crafting input buses of buffers
you don't really need them though since there's not that many recipes
and your processing is going to be limited by the LHC rates anyway
also the Beamcrafter can buffer particles
but it's only able to accept particles while a recipe is running
this may be changed to allow constant buffering at all times
but for now this is how it's going to be
just gonna quickly mention these because they exist
but they're all fairly easy to understand by reading the tooltips
the Beam Mirror allows you to turn a particle beam by 90 or 180 degrees
the Beam Stabilizer acts as a small buffer
allowing you to make an intermittent beam of high amount a constant beam of low amount
and the Beam Splitter allows you to split a mixed stream of particle packets into four separate configurable lines
OK, and here's a little bit of fun stuff for the nerds in here
I know you're out there
I said before that the LHC overclocking is a bit weird
and it's kind of its own thing, so
if you're interested in finding out how it actually works
this is how it works
we've got two equations
R equals R0 a to the N
and P equals R N squared
R is the accelerated rate
the rate with which you do collisions in the LHC
R0 is the initial rate
the input rate
a is the multiplication factor
which currently is 1.1
but that might be changed for balancing reasons
so I've just left it as a
N is the cycle count
and P is the power draw in amps of UV
in these two equations
you can solve for N in the bottom one
and plug it into the equation in the top
and then after a bit of simplification
you get the base relationship which is this
pretty ugly
there's not really much I can say with just this equation
so we ask the question
what happens if we overclock
remember that R determines crafting speed in the beam crafter
and P is the power
you can't really overclock the LHC by increasing the energy hatch
what I mean by overclock in this case is running more cycles because the power draw is going to increase
so the question becomes what happens if you run enough cycles that the power draw has increased by a factor of 4
in other words
if P becomes 4P, then what happens to rate
and I declare that R becomes k times R
the question is what is k
for a normal multiblock
k is equal to 4 or k is equal to 2 if it's perfectly overclocking or if it's not perfectly overclocking
but in the LHC case
it's a little more weird
so we transform P to 4P and we transform R to kR in the base relationship
and then we get the overclocked relationship
which is basically the same thing but P has become 4P and R has become kR
this still isn't really enough to say anything
so what we need to do is compare the two relationships
we compare the overclocked relationship with the base relationship by taking the ratios of the left hand sides and the right hand sides
we get this equation
after a bit of simplification
a lot of stuff cancels out
and we just get a relationship between k and R
you can try to solve for k
but it's not gonna work
you need a Lambert function and stuff
it's not worth your time
so just plot this implicitly
and then we can draw some conclusions
this is the plot where y is k and x is R over R0
and as you can see
it is very weird
keep in mind that normal multiblocks just have a constant y equals 2 or y equals 4 line
but the LHC has something that changes with time basically
as you run more cycles, the overclocking factor improves
and in fact it's worse than a regular overclock
until you get to about five times the beam rate that you started with
after that it's as good as a regular
and then it continues to increase, but not forever
it asymptotes to a perfect overclock
I tried to zoom out a bit here but it's really not obvious
you have to do a lot of cycles
like an unbelievable number of cycles to actually get to a perfect overclock
adjacent overclock factor
this is something I may tweak as well
because I have ...
actually this is a homework exercise for you if you're interested
let me let me state the problem clearly
introduce a constant c
which is a tunable parameter
which I can set
which determines the asymptotic value of the overclock in the large R over R0 limit
basically find a new equation or a new pair of equations that lets me choose what the asymptote is
the equations I have right now asymptote to four
but if I wanted to asymptote to 16 or something
what would the equations have to be
that's a fun little question
it's kind of hard
but I figured it out
and it's really really ugly
here's the answer
spoiler alert
it's really ugly
anyway that's my analysis
I hope you found this guide helpful
and I hope you enjoy the LHC
and if it's not fun let me know
and I am more than happy to change how it works so that it is fun
that is the most important thing, even more than realism
as much as it hurts me to say
anyway, enjoy
see you next time
大家好，欢迎来到HamCrop GTNH粒子物理指南
在这个视频中
我们将讨论即将推出的大型强子对撞机多块，它将在2.9中添加到GTNH
这个多块是我设计和实现的
嗯，主要是我。
在开发团队和GTNH社区的许多成员的帮助下
没错。
大型强子对撞机就是哈姆公司
如果您在日报上玩，您现在可以尝试LHC和所有其他新的2.9功能
请这样做并为我找到错误，以便我修复它们
谢谢。
在录制时，2.9仍在开发中
大型强子对撞机和光束制造仍然需要平衡和bug固定
检查固定评论，看看自此视频以来系统的工作方式是否发生了变化
细微的平衡变化不会在该评论中涵盖
大型强子对撞机是将被移除的旧紧凑型回旋加速器或彗星的替代品
LHC和光束制作多节使用现有的光束线力学
并且实际上与光束线多字节兼容
事实上，你甚至可以用大型强子对撞机来做光束线配方。
但在录制这段视频时，这还没有被广泛测试过。
我可以确认这是可能的
但如果在实际游戏中可行就不行了
光束线在技术上仍然是可选的
但考虑到LHC不是
我希望能看到更多的光束线
大型强子对撞机将是获得夸克平台释放催化剂的新方法
是的，长期的HamCrop粉丝现在可能正在制作链接
这个多重确实完全源于我对粒子物理过于迂腐
总之LHC现在有8级水位
在你得到大型强子对撞机之前可以使用的光束制造器
门未知粒子和量子异常
所有以前使用粒子作为物品的配方现在都使用粒子作为光束
粒子不再作为项目存在，未知粒子除外
首先，让我们介绍GTNH中粒子的基础知识
光束中的粒子以数据包的形式传播
类似于研究站计算包
粒子包有四个属性
类型、能量、数量和重点
type是粒子的类型
所以电子、介子、光子等等
能量是以电子伏特为单位的粒子的能量
数量，有时在这里和那里被不一致地称为速率，可以解释为数据包中单个粒子的数量
这就是在Beamcrafter中决定制作速度的因素
这是你想要最大化的数量吗？
焦点与大型强子对撞机和光束制造无关
但这是一个代表光束准直的量
这对光束线很重要
但我们会在这个视频中完全忽略它
接下来我们来谈谈大型强子对撞机是如何工作的
我将基于您已阅读工具提示以了解详细信息的假设继续
大型强子对撞机将任何带电粒子作为输入
并根据以下内容生成输出：
1.碰撞的能量和2.您从哪个模块绘制输出
大型强子对撞机有加速器和对撞机两种模式
它每秒循环一次
当达到玩家设置的加速循环计数时，自动从加速器切换到碰撞器
在界面中
如果你点击这个按钮
您可以设置两个值
目标光束能量和加速循环计数
一旦你设置好这些并打开LHC
它将开始加速入射光束
该输入光束在操作期间不能改变其四个参数中的任何一个
否则大型强子对撞机就会关闭
使用传入光束的值作为起点
大型强子对撞机将在加速模式下加速光束
意味着光束能量每周期增加一次
如果光束能量到达玩家设定的目标能量
进一步的LHC循环反而会增加电流束量
但是你怎么知道设定什么目标能量
光束能量只有一个用途
将粒子类型添加到潜在输出池中
如果加速光束能量为E
那么粒子碰撞时的碰撞能量是2倍E
现在可以出现在输出中的粒子类型只是所有质量为2E或更低的粒子
所以如果你瞄准一个质量为100千兆电子伏特的粒子
然后将目标能量设置为至少50千兆电子伏
那么碰撞是100
你可以得到这些粒子
增加超过你需要的能量没有任何好处
此外，并非所有粒子都可以出现在所有模块中
每个大型强子对撞机模块只能产生粒子的一个子集
你可以在NEI中看到这个
大型强子对撞机的能量消耗非常大
因为它是随时间二次增长的
它也随着光束的数量而缩放
也就是说，我已经对光束工匠中产生的制作速度如何与功率消耗进行了分析
我发现最好做尽可能多的循环
你做的周期越多，就越接近
你可以完美超频
此分析的详细信息在视频后面的可选高级部分中
哦，那真是太多了。
我们来谈谈如何利用这些粒子
Beamcrafter是一个多，需要流体，物品和粒子输入
一旦检测到输入物品和液体，飞船就开始
然后机器等待粒子输入
这为飞船提供了进步
没有粒子就意味着没有进步
如果粒子束中断，配方不会关闭
NEI显示了飞船所需的累积光束量
飞船运行时能量不断消耗
请注意，在记录时，beamcrafter不适用于缓冲区的制作输入总线
你真的不需要它们，因为没有那么多食谱。
无论如何，你的处理都会受到LHC速率的限制
Beamcrafter也可以缓冲粒子
但它只能在配方运行时接受粒子
这可以更改为允许始终保持恒定缓冲
但现在事情就是这样
我会很快提到这些，因为它们存在。
但通过阅读工具提示，它们都很容易理解
光束镜允许您将粒子束旋转90或180度
光束稳定器充当小缓冲区
让你可以制造高强度的间歇光束，低强度的恒定光束
Beam Splitter允许您将粒子包的混合流拆分为四个单独的可配置行
好的，这里有一些有趣的东西给书呆子们。
我知道你就在外面
我之前说过LHC超频有点怪
这是它自己的事情，所以
如果你想知道它到底是怎么工作的
这就是它的工作原理
我们有两个方程
R等于R0 a到N
P等于R N的平方
R是加速速率
大型强子对撞机的碰撞速率
R0是初始速率
输入速率
a是乘法因子
目前是1.1。
但出于平衡的原因，这可能会改变
所以我把它作为一个
N是循环计数
P是紫外线安培的功率消耗
在这两个方程中
你可以在底部求解N。
并将其插入顶部的方程
然后经过一点简化
你得到的基本关系是这样的
相当难看
就这个等式我没什么好说的
所以我们问这个问题
如果我们超频会发生什么
请记住，R决定了光束制作器中的制作速度
P是幂
你不能通过增加能量舱口来超频大型强子对撞机
在这种情况下，我所说的超频是指运行更多周期，因为功耗会增加。
所以问题变成了如果你运行足够多的循环，能量消耗增加了4倍会发生什么
换句话说
如果P变成4P，那么费率会发生什么？
我宣布R变成k乘以R
问题是什么是k
对于正常的多块
k等于4或k等于2，如果它是完美超频或不是完美超频
但在LHC案中
这有点奇怪
然后我们得到超频关系
这基本上是一回事，但P变成了4P，R变成了kR
这还不足以说明什么
所以我们需要做的是比较这两种关系
我们通过取左手边和右手边的比率来比较超频关系和基本关系
我们得到这个等式
经过一点简化
很多东西都抵消了
我们刚刚得到k和R之间的关系
你可以试着解决k
但这是行不通的
你需要一个Lambert函数之类的东西
不值得你花时间
所以只要隐式地绘制这个
然后我们可以得出一些结论
这是y是k，x是R除以R0的图
如你所见
这很奇怪
请记住，正常的多块只是有一个常数y等于2或y等于4行
但是大型强子对撞机有一些基本上随时间变化的东西。
当您运行更多周期时，超频因子会提高
事实上，这比常规超频更糟糕
直到你达到你开始时的5倍光束速率
之后它和普通的一样好
然后它继续增加，但不是永远
它渐近于完美的超频
我试着缩小一点，但真的不明显。
你必须做很多循环
就像难以置信的周期数量才能真正达到完美的超频
相邻超频因子
这也是我可能会调整的地方。
因为我有…
如果你们感兴趣的话这是你们的家庭作业
让我让我把问题说清楚
引入一个常数c
这是一个可调参数
我可以设置。
它确定了大R over R0限制中超频的渐近值
基本上找到一个新的方程或一对新的方程，让我选择渐近线是什么
我现在得到的等式是4
但是如果我想渐近线到16岁什么的
方程必须是什么？
这是个有趣的小问题
这有点难
但我想通了
而且真的真的很丑
这就是答案
剧透警报
真的很难看
不管怎样，这就是我的分析。
我希望你觉得这个指南有帮助
我希望你喜欢LHC
如果不好玩，请告诉我。
我非常乐意改变它的工作方式，让它变得有趣。
这是最重要的事情，甚至比现实主义更重要
尽管说出来让我很难过
不管怎样，享受吧
下次见